Never forget why you are the church.
go ahead and get right into it.
You can go ahead and turn your Bible to Revelation chapter 10.
Revelation chapter 10.
We'll be here and then in a little bit.
We'll be in Revelation 11.
So you can kind of just stay.
We got the notes right here if you need them, uh,
for anything to follow along.
All right, last week, we went over the angel
and the little book, and it was not going to
be long for God's judgment to be completed.
However, from this point that we are, there is more to
come, a lot more to come, actually.
And we saw the bittersweet reality of this in
Revelation chapter 10, verse 8 through 11.
It says this.
And the voice which I heard from heaven spake unto
him, unto me again, and say, go and take the
little book, which is open in the hand of the angel, which stand at the Panisthean upon the earth.
And I went unto the angel and said unto him, give me the little book.
And he said unto me, take it and eat it up, and it shall
make thy belly bitter, but it shall be in thy mouth, sweet as honey.
And I took the little book out of the angel's hand.
I ate it up, and it was in my mouth, sweet as honey, and as soon
as I had eaten it, my belly was bitter.
And he said unto me, thou must prophesy again before
many peoples and nations and tongues and kings.
Remember, to a believer, the end means
the beginning of eternity with Jesus.
But to an unbeliever, the end means eternal separation
from God, something that we cannot fathom.
But the Bible describes it as eternal torment where
there is weeping and gnashing of teeth.
Now, there is a certain conversational strategy
when you come across an unbeliever who claims
that there is no afterlife.
Have any of you ever talked to someone who says, well, I'm just going to die, nothing happens after.
It's a very popular view, right?
annihilationism, right?
When you die, you just, you just become annihilated, as if
you never were born or anything.
Um, I have a certain, and it's not unique to me.
I'm sure you've used it as well, but if you look at
it in a certain perspective, right?
Uh, this is more common and you think.
A lot of people believe this because it's easier to believe in nothing than
it is to believe in something when it comes to the afterlife.
There's nothing, then there's no accountability.
Right?
But, Again, we were created
for eternity and we cannot get away from that truth,
even if they claim not to believe it.
But here is what I like to say to people that think that, right?
If I am wrong, and they are right.
So in other words, I'm wrong about everything the
Bible says, there is no afterlife.
It's just, I die and I go into the ground, I rot, right?
Uh, what happens is I live a morally good life.
Right?
Because I'm adhering to a good set of morals.
I am just talking about it if I'm wrong.
Well, no, we're not wrong, but if I was, right?
If we were, I enjoy a sense of purpose.
And I die and that's it.
Not too bad of an option here, amen?
To live a good life, morally, to live with a
purpose, to live in a community like a church.
And even if we're wrong, we die, and we live the good life.
But if I'm right.
And they're wrong.
We're right, and they're wrong.
Um, they spend eternity in hell, understanding exactly why they're there.
Uh, God forbid we choose that or
allow anyone to just freely choose that.
You say, what do you mean by that?
We've got to tell them the gospel.
We got to tell them the good news.
You say, what if they don't believe it?
That not on our.
That's not on us.
We share the gospel.
We give the good news.
We allow the Holy Spirit to do the rest of the work.
Amen?
Again, that's not a coin toss that I'm willing to make.
Our souls are not worth risking.
So we then moved along to the 2 witnesses.
We talk about how the ministry we see them have for
their time during the tribulation is how the church should operate today as well.
We are protected by God.
We ought to be a place and a people that God does mighty works through.
If there be a fire out of our mouths, may it
be the word of God, right?
You do realize, listen, I know there's a lot of opinions on,
you know, divine, does God still heal?
Is there divine healing?
Is there mighty works and wonders and signs and all things?
And I have my certain perspective on that stuff.
I do believe there's certain things that was done and
allowed to establish the church.
I believe the church is established, even though we see
the modern church running away from God more and more.
So, I'll go ahead and tell you, I don't
see it as impossible that God, again, shows us mighty
things because literally, we don't,
we don't have, we have so many churches that are, that are reprobate.
They're falling away from the faith, right?
And so, but here's the thing.
A church should be a place where awesome things happen.
A church should be a place where people come in and if they if
they need comfort, if they need encouragement, if they need healing,
listen, it may not be healing like you come down to the altar,
I put my hand on you, start convulsing.
Listen, that's not what we, that's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about prayer that works because we are praying to an almighty God.
That's what I'm talking about, right?
We've seen it happen in this very church.
God answer prayer.
Mighty healings done through the will of God through praying.
So again, we are protected by God.
We ought to be a place in people that God does mighty works through.
And if we're going to ever spew out fire.
hold on.
Man, that just came across me right then.
My goodness gracious, I got a mic square in my mouth too.
Anyway, my bad.
Oh, Lord.
And that left us revelation 1114, right?
The 2nd woe was passed and behold, the 3rd woe cometh quickly.
So we're going to look at what comes next.
Let's pray.
Father, we thank you, Lord, for this night.
We thank you for your word.
God, I pray you give me wisdom, power, understanding to preach your word.
And it's in Jesus name, we pray.
Everybody said?
Amen.
We're in Revelation 11.
Verses 15 through 19.
It says this.
And the 7th angel sounded, and there were great
voices in heaven saying, the kingdoms of this world are become the
kingdoms of our Lord, and of his Christ, and he shall reign
forever and ever.
And the 4 and 20 elders which sat before God on their seats fell
upon their faces and worship God, saying, we give thee
thanks, O Lord God Almighty, which art and wast and art to come
because thou hast taken to thee thy great power and hast reigned.
And the nations were angry, and thy wrath is come, and the time of the dead,
and that they should be judged, thou shouldest give reward unto thy servants,
the prophets, and to the saints, and them that fear thy name
small and great, and shouldest destroy them, which destroy the earth.
And the temple of God was open in heaven.
There was seen in his temple the ark of his testament, and there were
lightnings and voices and thunderings and an earthquake and great hail.
There is much to learn in this small portion of text.
And although we do not see the full effects of this trumpet
until chapter 16,
when the bowls of wrath are poured out.
We do learn much from this introduction here.
So we're going to go pretty much verse by verse
and kind of just go over some important details.
So we look at verse 15 again, it says, and the 7th angel sounded,
and there were great voices in heaven saying, the kingdoms of this
world are become the kingdoms of our Lord, and it was
Christ, and he shall reign forever and ever.
Now, this is different from the last
6 Trumpets in that there is a multitude of voices heard.
This mighty chorus indicates that the end is
indeed near.
But what did they say?
It says, they say right here, the kingdoms of this world or become the kingdoms
of our Lord, of his crisis?
Is our reign forever and ever?
This has been prophesied all throughout scripture.
The earthly kingdom of Christ will
be established.
We will reign with Christ.
I believe, a literal 1000 years upon this earth.
Um, we see this in the Old Testament book such as Ezekiel,
Daniel, Zechariah.
This is going to be established at the 2nd coming of Christ.
Therefore, we can understand this 7th
trumpet to chronologically reach to
Christ's return.
I know it's hard to put chronological terms in Revelation
because it's over here over there, over everywhere, right?
Trust me, I get it.
I'm reading it myself each week.
And it's hard to follow, but we know that this this
7th trumpet is going to go to the 2nd
coming of Christ.
Right now, the world is ruled by Satan.
But it's a temporary condition.
By the way, it doesn't take a long look to see
that Satan is doing a great job at ruling.
I'm going to mention this a little bit on Sunday, just a little bit.
Um, but the fact that we
celebrate what we celebrate,
Support what we support in our society.
Uh, I'm just going ahead and tell you right now, we are,
um, we are in a bad condition.
Now, that's nothing you.
There's nothing you understand.
Listen, like when people I was teaching the kids this morning, the
questions about Israel, why are they so wicked?
Why are they so this?
Man, read your Bible.
Israel's always been rebellious.
They've always worshiped false idols.
They've always, you know, made
sacrifices to Molic, and they say, well, well,
Israel by capital is the most aborting nation, and
they've been that way for a long time.
We can't have reasons, bias.
They've had their eyes darkened for a long,
long time.
But why I say that is because, listen, when we look
at our society, what we see is that Satan,
when things don't, when you look at scripture and
you look up and see what's happening in our culture and it's
completely opposite, that's because the opposer of
scripture is ruling the world right now.
And he's doing so because God is allowing him to.
Right?
You understand what I'm saying?
Have you ever given your kids, not that, you know, obviously Satan
is not, he's a creation of God, but he's not a child of
God, obviously, but have you even given your kids, just, hey, the ability, hey, you know what?
You get to do whatever you want tonight.
Just do, and they make a mess, and they
break up the couch, and they make forts,
and you're thinking, man, I gave you a little bit of freedom, and
you messed everything up, right?
Listen, the enemy on purpose is messing
everything up, and God is allowing him to do it because it is a part of
his perfect plan and will.
Amen?
You with me?
But what I was gonna say about Sunday, you know, and
I know this is, this, you may be, I don't know which, where
you stand on this, but this whole Lindsay Clancy trial has
gotten me just, it's, it's gotten my brain just bamboozled,
that, uh, and, and the reason, I've been bamboozled
about it, but it was like the, the, the,
the interview they've done with these jurors.
Guys, it's crazy.
I mean, literally, a juror said, well, he just couldn't get over how viciously
she murdered her kids.
Well, me neither.
How can we get over it?
What are you talking about?
That is the case.
If she didn't do that, we wouldn't be here.
You understand what I'm saying?
But you know what the world says?
Hey, you know what?
And she was, she was, she was, she just snapped.
She was not in her right mind.
my other thing.
Listen, we overlook evil and we call it good
and we take we see good and we call it evil.
That one juror that made it go into a mistrial.
What is he doing?
He's being attacked because he stood up for what was right.
That's what our world is today.
And by the way, don't be surprised when it starts hitting the
church more and more that as we stand up for truth, we
get attacked and attacked and attacked.
But again, Jesus will return.
en?
He will rule and reign.
Amen?
And his rule will be forever.
We continue in Revelation 11, 16 through 17.
And the 4 and 20 elders, which sat before God in
their seats, fell upon their faces and worshiped God, saying,
we give thee thanks, O Lord God Almighty, which art and wast
and art to come, which thou hast taken to thee, thy great power and
hast reigned, because thou hast taken to thy great power and hast reign.
Who are the 24 elders?
Now, they are mentioned quite a bit in Revelation?
As a matter of fact, they are mentioned 11 times throughout this book.
But there isn't a true description
or explanation of who they actually are.
And guess what?
Just like everything in Revelation, there's much speculation, right?
There's a lot of different opinions about who they are.
The primary thoughts are three.
They are either glorified humans.
Angels, and some even believe them to be of astral mythology.
Now, I'm gonna go ahead and debunk the first one real quick, okay?
Astral mythology is exactly that, mythology.
Okay?
Just to give you some description of what this actually is.
Let me give you a definition of this.
Astromethology refers to a theoretical framework
that interprets myths and religious narratives
as encoded representations of astronomical phenomena,
particularly the movements and characteristics of celestial bodies.
This approach emerged from Babylonian,
religious thought and became influential in ancient Mediterranean cultures.
Now, I know that was a whole lot that I just said there.
In other words, it's a bunch of garbage.
Does that make sense?
That was just a long way to say, it's not real.
In other words, it's just mythology, right?
So right at the gate, we know that this is not it.
By the way, if you ever see Babylonian culture.
Keep on reading Revelation.
We do not want to be identified with anything
Babylonian.
You understand what I'm saying?
And we'll learn that more as we go through Evelation, but anything
that comes from Babylon is sinful and wicked.
I don't care how beautiful it was.
I don't care how many, you know, wonders of the world they built.
I don't care.
They were wicked and far from God.
Okay?
Then you have the view that they are angels.
Now let me ask you something.
And this is some...
When I debate scripture with people.
Okay?
Which is sometimes fun, and sometimes not.
Does that make sense?
I love when people love to debate scripture, they don't know scripture.
That makes it no fun.
They're just throwing out opinion.
And I like to talk about actual text.
But...
What was scripture?
How is scripture given to us?
God inspired people, right?
to do what?
Write it down, right?
You see what I'm saying?
That was not a trick question.
Thank y'all very much.
God inspired people to write down
scripture, right?
Do you think God is good at inspiration?
Do you think he's he's detailed?
Yeah, okay.
Do you think that he knows what he's doing?
Okay.
This is all gonna come to here in just a second.
When you look at scripture,
I need you to know that when God writes a word and
uses a word, He's meaning that word.
And if he writes another word, he means that other word.
You say, what in the world are you saying?
Do you think that John knows how to write down the word angel?
You understand what I'm saying here?
Because a lot of people believe it's 24 elders are angels.
If that was the case, we've seen it time and time again, right,
all throughout Revelation that he speaks of angels,
he actually does right at the beginning of this text, right?
Revelation 11.15, that word angel means a messenger,
angel, a being that is to deliver a message or perform a task.
And in verse 16, the term elders mean, an
older, elder, presbyter, in general, a leader whose authority
comes in principle, from the wisdom associated with
age, in the church, a particular kind of leader whose
responsibilities included, directing churches.
These are very different words here.
You've got angel, and you've got elder.
Now, it's important to note that most Bible scholars.
They don't see these elders as simply pastors from New Testament churches.
Right?
Rather, the term signifies maturity and wisdom.
In the Old Testament, it has many more layers, right?
The noun, Zack can usually translated elder
in the Old Testament Hebrew, can simply mean old
man or age person, but it comes from the verb, Zack and
meaning to be or become old, age and experience were
expected, to result in wisdom and the ability
to rule with prudence.
In other words, these elders are not celestial
beings, they are not angels.
They are human representatives of God's
people in God's presence symbolizing
the church in heaven.
So they are our representatives in heaven, worshiping
God, showing what is to come.
Now, that we know who they are, what are they doing?
Well, they have their faces fallen before God worshiping him.
Now, what are they saying?
Revelation 1117, saying we give these thanks, O Lord God Almighty,
which art and was and art to come because thou hast taken to thee
thy great power and hast reigned.
This echoes, this truth in Revelation one.8.
I'm the Alfred, the Omega says the Lord God, who is and was,
and who is to come, the Almighty.
Again, in Revelation 4, verse 8, and the 4 living
creatures, each of them having 6 wings, are full of eyes around
and within, and day and night, they do not cease to say, holy,
holy, holy, is the Lord God, the Almighty, who was, and
who is, and who is to come.
By the way, you cannot be the almighty.
That is the all powerful one, if you are not also the beginning and the end.
If you were created, that means there's something more powerful than you.
Does that make sense?
God is the uncreated creator.
Therefore, he is the all powerful almighty one.
Now, what do I mean by this?
Well, notice who they're giving thanks to.
Revelation 1117, saying we give thanks, O Lord God, almighty.
And we've already talked about what Almighty means, all powerful one, but this term Lord
God is using scripture many times to refer to God.
But when is the 1st time that we see this term God right here?
Well,
What is the 1st book in the Bible?
So Genesis one, verse one says what?
In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth.
That term God, that name God is Elohim.
They give thanks, though, to the Lord God.
So they have 2 names combined.
We see in Genesis chapter 2, verse 4.
This is the account of the heavens and the earth when they were created in
the day that the Lord God made earth and heaven, the Lord God.
This is 2 Hebrew names put together, Yahweh,
Elohim, the redeemer, creator.
He is the uncreated one.
He is the almighty, the all powerful one.
Therefore, he takes the power that belongs to him
and he reigns.
This hymn of praise and thanksgiving from these elders is an anticipation
of the 2nd coming of Christ and the establishment of
his rule on the earth.
And guess what?
No one and nothing can do anything about it.
You know, it's interesting.
We talk about how, um, people wish,
in that time, the Bible says that people wish they would can die,
and they can't, and they run through the hills on these things.
There's this big movement right now.
It's not really a new movement, so I don't want to say new movement, but all these
mega rich people making bunkers.
for what is to come.
Can I explain something to you?
I'm not saying if I didn't have the money, I wouldn't make one for me.
I don't know, because I'm kind of OCD and weirded out about that kind of stuff, you know?
I feel like if we ever get nuked, I hope they nuke,
like, right above our heads so we don't feel nothing.
You know what I'm saying?
I don't want to be dying three years later of radiation poison, okay?
Turn green or something, glow.
I don't want that.
Just take me out instantly.
Amen?
No?
Y'all wanna, y'all wanna suffer?
Okay, anyway.
But listen, a bunker's not gonna protect you from what is to come.
Just not.
I mean, I mean, listen, people, what they do, what people do is
they try, they take, everyone knows something is coming.
Does that make sense?
Everyone knows something bad is going to happen.
But they refuse to believe what God says about it.
And so what they do is, we see it in movies all the time.
Right?
We see 2012 and we see, you know, independence.
All these things that happen.
We try to think that it's going to be aliens.
We think it's going to be a natural disaster.
Listen, all that stuff is gonna happen.
I know about aliens, but there's going to be demonic locusts come out of the abyss
that's as alien as it gets from me.
Amen.
I don't need to see any more aliens.
But what I'm trying to say is this is all gonna happen.
Something bad is going to happen.
We just get told that it's judgment.
It's God's wrath upon the earth, right?
And we also know how to get out of it.
And it's a lot, it's a lot, when I say cheaper, understand?
I'm talking about financial means.
It's a lot cheaper than a bunker.
It's just giving your life to Christ.
Amen.
And when you give your life to Christ, you live.
Revelation 1118 says this, and the nations were angry, and
thy wrath is come, and the time of the dead, and they should be judged,
uh, that they should be judged, and that thou
shouldest give reward of thy service to prophets, and to the saints, and to
them that fear thy name, small and great, and shouldest
destroy them which destroy the earth.
The world, again, right now is acting as if they can stop who is coming to reign.
Their efforts are futile in vain.
His wrath has come and will be finished with the 7th trumpet.
This will bring judgment on those who did not fear God.
Hebrews 9.27 tells us and is appointed for men to die once,
but after this judgment.
What does it mean in fear of God?
It means to revere him.
God God is the is the reverend God.
He is the one who can inflict terror.
Therefore, we revere him.
There's a reason I know people mean it well in all
things and we just grow up doing...
There's a reason why I don't, and I've told you this.
I don't necessarily love being called a reverend.
I do not inflict terror.
But I serve the one who does.
Amen?
And there was a time, not long ago on Wednesday night, that
I raised my hand in thunder.
Lord.
I don't know if you remember that or not.
Does anyone remember that?
No?
You remember that?
Put my hand up?
Y'all remember that?
Okay.
Just knowing.
I'm not, I'm not reverend, but I serve the one who can strike you down.
I'm kidding.
All right, but the end is near, right?
Those who have put their faith in Jesus will go.
This is a very tough crowd tonight.
I need you to know that.
Those who put their faith in Jesus will go to the mercy seat,
and those who have not will go to the great white throne judgment.
We'll see that later on in the book, but they'll be cast into the lake of fire.
We then see an interesting occurrence in the next verse.
Revelation 11, 19, and the temple of God was opened
in heaven, and they were seen in his temple, the ark of his testament.
That's the ark of the covenant, and there were lightnings and voices and
thunderings and an earthquake in great hail.
I like how the home and New Testament commentary explains this.
It says this.
John's vision of God began with a throne room in
Revelation 4, with the addition of a golden
incense altar, the place that come to be God's temple in
heaven, now there is further temple language, Israel's
earthly tabernacle, and its later temple, has been famous for an inner
shrine, the most holy place behind the thick curtain.
Remember, that was broken when Jesus died.
Behind the curtain, the earthly arc, chest, ark of the
covenant, symbolized the gracious covenant relationship between
God and humanity.
The Ark of the Covenant was the most sacred, tangible
presession Israel ever had.
It was lost when Babylon, remember Babylon, bad things.
Destroyed Jerusalem in the 6th century BC, and it's been lost ever since.
So, literally, John was beholding something in this vision
that no human had seen for centuries.
It was a glimpse of what was to come.
Heaven was near, the covenant that God had made to be
with his people for eternity was about to take place and be completed.
However, the judgment sequence is beginning.
Judgment proceeds in the place that best displayed the heavenly
representation of God's establishing a relationship with humanity.
God could judge mankind solely because he is the creator,
his judgment proceeds because he has done everything to establish
a covenant of redemption with humanity.
I'm teaching, uh, in all the branch I'm teaching.
We're going through the acts of the drama of scripture, right?
It's just a way to illustrate and kind of, you know, structure it.
I made sure they understood that this is not a fairy tale,
but we are gonna look at it, act one, act two, act three.
Act one, of course, God establishes his kingdom.
We see creation.
Act two, right?
There's rebellion in the kingdom.
We see the fall.
Listen, after that, God chooses Israel, we
see Cain and Abel, 2 different really, really religions
and belief systems put in place.
Kane is work based, and then Abel, who is replaced with
Seth, is faith based.
Right?
By the way, that's every single religion now.
Every religion is either work based or faith based.
I don't care.
name whichever one you want, right?
If it's work based, it's man trying to get to God.
In any way they can.
If it's faith-based, we understand and believe that God can demand to make a way.
You see what I'm saying?
It's a very different situation here, okay?
But we see that redemption
in that moment was initiated.
And so tonight as we await these things to come to pass,
Do you revere God?
I mean, truly do you revere him?
Do you respect him in such a way that you understand and acknowledge that he is the one
who can inflict terror?
He is the redeemer, creator.
Not only did he create us, but he desires to redeem us.
Not only did he create us, but he desires to know us and have a relationship with us.
Guys, listen, we don't have to be scared of him, but we better fear him.
Amen.
So it has about it, and eyes close all this place before we get into prayer time.